# Jay Shepherd

London, England, United Kingdom



jaykshepherd92@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/jay-s-62653463

## Summary

\*\*\*Currently open to contract and perm roles working on a backend stack\*\*\* as current development phase ending soon in current role.

Preferred language: Python Preferred framework: FastAPI Preferred database: Postgres Preffered deployment: K8s

I am a hard-working, open-minded, reliable, and positive individual from which I pride myself on being a key goto figure when representing a company. My natural interest in technology enables me to be considered a rapid learner when it comes to software or physical hardware.

Freelance Python developer for the last 2 years via various freelance platforms, experience building desktop applications, web apps, mobile apps using Kivvy. Python Libraries that I am comfortable with are, Selenium, Pandas, Bokeh, Django, Flask, Kivvy, Tkinter, SQLalchemy and more.

### **Experience**

### **Backend Software Engineer**

Dhani

Feb 2021 - Present (7 months +)

Working on a new project for a large scale business presents its challenges and it is part of my role to ensure any new feature requests and bug fixes are delivered for each sprint.

Technologies used;

- Python
- FastAPI
- Postgresql
- Kubernetes

Working in this role allows me to write clean, readable code ready for end users towards a weekly deployment timeline. Duties including but not limited too, creating API's, update and maintain databases across development, ga and production environments. Writing functions and scripts to enhance internal or user experience. Planning the logic behind new features or improvements.

# Freelance Python Developer

Fiverr and Upwork Freelancers (Buyers and Sellers)

Mar 2019 - Present (2 years 6 months +)

Freelance Python developer for the last 2 years via various freelance platforms, experience building desktop applications, web apps and mobile apps. Python Libraries that I am comfortable with are, Selenium, Pandas, Bokeh, Django, Flask, Kivvy, Tkinter and more.

#### MrSite ? Website Support Agent

**MrSite** 

Mar 2016 - Sep 2019 (3 years 7 months)

As a Web Support Agent at Mr. Site my role was to be the face of the company when a customer wishes to achieve a goal or solve a problem relating to their website. This job allowed me to broadcast my natural people skills when helping customers but also add value to the process by using my HTML skills to overcome front-end website hurdles. On top of this, I have built up a broad knowledge around website hosting, SQL servers, PHP scripts and domain name servers.

#### N3 Dynamics CRM Presales Consultant

N3

Nov 2011 - Dec 2015 (4 years 2 months) **RESPONSIBILITIES** 

To work within the UK Microsoft practice providing custom solutions using my expertise and expert knowledge of Dynamics CRM to manage exciting solutions for our clients and using my development expertise to help deliver large and complex projects across the Microsoft Stack.

- Document business needs, identify gaps between business needs and standard application functionality, design and document solutions that fill the gaps, and provide detailed business requirements specifications for developers.
- · Develop and maintain business process documentation and consider compliance in all business process analysis and redesign activities.
- Perform application configuration, testing and evaluation to ensure quality and consistency.
- Develop, document, and execute test plans to assess the integrity and accuracy of business processes, module functionality setups and modifications, enhancements, customization, and patches
- Develop and maintain end user training documentation and deliver training as required

Microsoft Dynamics is a flexible, powerful business solution for customer relationship management (CRM) and enterprise resource planning (ERP) that can help make your people more productive and can grow with your business.

#### Education



#### Zenos IT Academy

Information Technology 2009 - 2010



#### Southfields Community College

2003 - 2008

# **Licenses & Certifications**

Comptia A+ - CompTIA

- Microsoft Certified Desktop Support Technician Microsoft
- IT Diploma Level 3 Zenos IT Training
- Full-Stack Software Development Diploma Code Institute

#### **Skills**

Python (Programming Language) • FastAPI • Flask • PostgreSQL • SQLAlchemy • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • API Development • Back-End Web Development • Kubernetes • Amazon Web Services (AWS)